XIU LI

lixiulive@gmail.com \diamond lixiu15@mails.tsinghua.edu.cn

RESEARCH INTEREST

My research interests lie broadly in computer vision, machine learning and computational photography. I'm now particularly focusing on 3D vision including performance capture, neural rendering/view synthetis, SfM and scene representation. I also spare some time on low-level vision including deblur, super-resolution, compressive imaging and various image restoration problems. My research aims at faithfully capturing, manipulating and presenting our real world.

EDUCATION

Tsinghua University

Dec, 2021 (expected)

Ph.D.

Department of Automation Advisor: Qionghai Dai

Tsinghua University

Aug, 2011-July, 2015

B.Eng

Department of Automation

EXPERIENCE

Microsoft Research Asia

Mar. 2021 - now

Beijing, CN

· Group: Media Computing

Carnegie Mellon University

Visiting Scholar

Research Intern

Sep,2017 - Aug,2019

Pittsburgh PA, USA

- · Mentor: Yaser Sheikh, Hongdong Li
- · Working on single view 3D human pose estimation, dense keypoint pose estimation and full body performance capture.

PUBLICATIONS

Refereed

- 1. **X. Li**, Z. Li, Q. Dai, 'Multi-task single-pixel imaging with an end-to-end flow of joint optimization', Optical Letters(in revision).
- 2. X. Zhang, L. An, T. Yu, X. Li, K. Li, Y. Liu, '4D Association Graph for Realtime Multi-person Motion Capture Using Multiple Video Cameras', CVPR 2020(oral)
- 3. X. Li, H. Li, H. Joo, Y. Liu, Y. Sheikh, 'Structure from Recurrent Motion: From Rigidity to Recurrency', CVPR 2018.

Preprints

- 1. **X. Li**, J. Suo, W. Zhang, X. Yuan, Q. Dai, 'Universal and Flexible Optical Aberration Correction using Deep-Prior Based Deconvolution'.
- 2. **X. Li**, Y. Liu, H. Joo, Q. Dai, Y. Sheikh, 'Capture Dense: Full-body Markless Motion Capture with Full-body Parsing', arxiv:1812.01783

SERVICES

• Reviewer for recent CVPR, ICCV, ECCV, AAAI, ACCV, WACV

SKILL

Programming LanguagesC/C++,Python,MatlabToolsOpenCV,OpenGL,Pytorch

AWARDS AND RECOGNITIONS

• 1st Place and 6th Mission finisher of 2013 International Aerial Robotics Competition